

DOST Form 11 LIST OF PERSONNEL INVOLVED

(1) Title Program: Grant in Aid Project: Development of a Non-dairy Probiotic Drink Using Coconut Sap as a Substrate		(2) Project Leader/Gender: Dr. Ma. Edelwina M. Blase/F		(3) Implementing Agency: Marinduque State College			
(5) Designation		(6) Remuneration		(7) Percent Time			
(4) Personnel/Gender	In Office	For This Particular Project (include Terms of Reference/Duties and Responsibilities)	In Office (Salary)	For This Particular Project	(a) This Project	(b) Other Project	(8) Highest Educational Attainment/ Discipline (Field of Specialization)
Ma. Edelwina M. Blase		Project Leader -Oversee the implementation of the project -Coordinate with the DOST in the implementation			6 units deloading (6 hours/week)		Ph.D. in Food Science
Christine Joy M. Manato		SRS 1 (Food Technologist) -Facilitate the research activities of the project -Submit necessary reports verified by the project leader			100%		BS in Food Technology
To be hired		Support staff -Assist the Science Research Specialist in the			100%		

-Record and assist in preparation of reports			
CERTIFIED CORRECT:	NOTED:		
Ma. Edelwina M. Blase Project Leader	Agency Head or Authorized Representative		

DOST Form 11 LIST OF PERSONNEL INVOLVED

I. General Instruction: Submit through the DOST Project Management Information System (DPMIS), http://dpmis.dost.gov.ph, this form for each component project. This form should accompany DOST Form 7. Executive Summary for the Annual Progress Report. Upon completion of the program/project, this shall accompany DOST Form 15. Executive Summary for the Terminal Report and DOST Form 16. Terminal Audited Financial Report. Also, submit four (4) copies of this form. Use Arial font, 11 font size.

II. Operational Definition of Terms:

1. Title- the identification of the Program and the component project.

Program- refers to a group of interrelated or complementing S&T projects that require an interdisciplinary or multidisciplinary approach to meet established goal(s) within a specific time frame.

Project- refers to the basic unit in the investigation of specific S&T problem/s with predetermined objective/s to be accomplished within a specific time frame.

- 2. Project Leader- refers to the person who plans, organizes and supervises the overall activities of a project.
- **3. Implementing Agency** the primary organization involved in the execution of a program/project which can be a public or private entity
- **4. Personnel** composed of the Project Leader and project staff, who are directly involved in the implementation of the project, and indicating the gender whether a Male "M" or a Female "F".
- **5. Designation** the official position/title of each staff in the agency/office and in the particular project. Include Terms of Reference/Duties and Responsibilities in the project.
- 6. Remuneration- the salary/compensation of each staff in the office and in the particular project.
- 7. Percent Time- proportion of the working time devoted to the particular project.
- 8. Highest Educational Attainment- the highest degree earned including field of specialization of each staff.



MA. EDELWINA MONTEREY BLASE

EDUCATION

POST GRADUATE UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES, LOS BANOS

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY in Food Science

2007-2011

Scholarship Granted CHED-HEDP-FDP, JUNE 2007-2010

DA-BAR THESIS SUPPORT

POSTGRADUATE UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES, LOS BANOS

Master of Science in Food Science

2000-2002

Scholarship Granted CHED-POST BACCALAUREATE, JUNE 2000-

MARCH 2002

COLLEGE UNIVERSITY OF THE PHILIPPINES, LOS BANOS

Bachelor of Science in Food Technology

1980-1985

March 12, 2018- to date Vice President for Research, Extension & Development

July2017-March 11,2018 Executive Director for Research & Development

May 28, 2012- June 2017 **Research Director -** Marinduque State College

June 1998 to date Faculty – Instructor 1--Associate Professor 3

Marinduque State College Tanza , Boac Marinduque

Quality Control Supervisor ADCO Resources Inc

April 15 1990-May 1998 Maysilo, Malabon Metro Mla.

Quality Control Inspector SLORD DEVELOPMENT CORP.

April 1988-1990 Navotas Fishport Complex

Navotas, Metro Manila

MEMBERSHIP IN ACADEMIC/PROFESSIONAL SOCIETIES

1985	PAFT, INC.	Member
2001	KKP, Southern Tagalog Chapter	Associate Member
2011	Philippine Fruits Association	Member
2012	Mycological Society of the Philippines	Member
2012	ISSAAS Phil	Member
2013	ISO Development Educ. Institute	Member
2013	Pair Inc.	Member
2015 2018	NRCP PHILARM	Associate Member Member

RESEARCHES CONDUCTED:

Title of Researches	Year Conducted
Development and Sustainability of Bioenergy Feedstock (MMSU-	2018- just starting
MSC Partnership)	
Development of Food and Non-Food products from Abalone	2017-2019 June
Integrated Indian mango Processing Facility-DOST-4B	2016-on-going
Product Development of Malunggay, Ginger and Coconut flour	2014
Product Development of Arrowroot	2013
Product Development of Rukam and other Tropical Fruit trees	2012
Utilization of Tannia Cormels for diverse products	2012
The Potential of Tropical Almond Fruit/Talisay (<i>Terminalia catappa</i>)	2012
for diverse food products	•01•
Acceptability of Singapor fries from purple and white variety	2012
Singapor (Xanthosoma, sagittifolium) Product Development of Mushroom	2011
-	-
Controlling Acridity in Tannia (Xanthosomasagittifolium(L) Schott cv White & Purple) Tubers Using Various Processing Treatments	2009-2010
Physiology of Tannia Tubers Stored at ambient temperature	2009
Acceptability of Bakery Products from Singapor Tubers or Yautia (Xanthosomaspp, Family: Araceae	2009
Ethyl Acetate Formation in Fermented Coconut Sap Distillate	2008
(Lambanog)	
Diversified Products from Gabing San Fernando / Yautia	2006
(Xanthosoma spp.)Tubers	
Optimization of Rice Flour Traits for the Production of Indigenous	2002
Recipes	
Textured Vegetable Protein Utilization	NRCP-UPLB, 1987
Coconut Sap Beverages	PCARRD-UPLB, 1986
Utilization of Coconut Sap for Non-Alcoholic Beverages	1984







Brgy. Tanza, Boac, Marinduque



0910329022



sirch.otanam@gmail.com

SexFemaleCivil StatusSingleCitizenshipFilipino

Religion Roman Catholic

Height 5'4

Weight 127.87 lbs.

Date of BirthPlace of BirthOdiongan, Romblon

EDUCATION

2015-2019

College: University of the Philippines Visayas

Degree: Bachelor of Science in Food Technology

SKILLS

- ✓ Computer and Microsoft Software Literate
- ✓ Good in Scientific and Technical Writing
- ✓ Familiar with Laboratory Protocols
- ✓ Research and Strategy
- ✓ Teamwork

ORGANIZATION

Philippine Association for Food Technologist-IOTA Chapter

CERTIFICATES

Civil Service Professional Exam Board Passer

Facilitator in the Convergence and Livelihood Assistance for ARBs Project on December 19, 2020

Committee on MSC 6th Regional Science and Technology Conference on June 29, 2021

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2020 - Present

Marinduque State College

- Research, Development, Extension, and Training
- -Works as a Science Research Specialist I
- -Assists in the making of the MSC Journals, the official biannual publication of the College
- -Attend Research and Development related meetings with other institutions and stakeholders
- -Assist the officials and faculty members in developing and conducting school or department-level research and surveys, including guidance in developing survey instruments, procedures and conducting data analysis;
- -Assist in meetings, trainings, or seminars conducted by the department
- -Crafts research project proposals related to food sector for external funding

- -Organizes with the Director for Research, Development and Publication the College biannual Regional In-house review
- -Assists in monitoring and evaluation of ongoing research projects and ensure that the objectives of the projects are met
- -Undertake administrative tasks assigned by the immediate supervisor
- -Prepare quarterly accomplishment report of the Research, Development, Extension and Training Department and renders technical services to other units of the department for efficient delivery of service

February 2020 - August 2020

Marinduque State College

- **❖** Research, Development, Extension, and Training
- -Works as a Science Research Assistant in DOST-PCAARRD project entitled, "Program on Support to the University's Strategies in Technology Acceleration Initiatives by Nurturing (SUSTAIN) the Intellectual Property and Technology Business Management (IP-TBM) Offices of the Consortia Member Agencies (Phase II)" under the Intellectual Property and Publication Office of the Research and Extension Department
- -Assists in Product Development (Food) activities of the Vice President (RDET)
- -Renders technical service to other units

June 2018-July 2018

Food Development Center Taguig

- **Department: Microbiology**
- -Worked as an assistant of Science Analysts in Microbiology Laboratory and performed duties such as observation of periodical laboratory protocols (SOPs) and assistance in conduction of food analyses
 - **Department: Product Development**

- -Assisted in the scientific project of the institution regarding the Arsenic and Cadmium content of Philippine Rice and performed duties and activities covered by the project such as soil test and sample preparation
- -Rendered services to other units/ offices of the department such as the Shelf Life Testing laboratory and Thermal Processing Plant

TRAININGS ATTENDED

DOST-PCHRD – RESEARCH FAIRNESS

MHRDC – BASIC RESEARCH METHODOLOGY

MSC - PHO - BASIC LIFE SUPPORT

REFERENCES

Dr. Ma Edelwina M. Blasé VP for Research, Development, Extension and Training dhel4blase@yahoo.com

Engr. Ana Fe N. Molato ITSO Manager and Technology Transfer Officer

Anne_nunez14@yahoo.com

Prof. Panchito Labay panchito.labay@yahoo.com

LANGUAGE







TAGALOG ENGLISH

HILIGAYNON